[Music]
from Lagos the nation's commercial
Capital this is the news at
10 live from channels television
reporting
[Music]
tonight hello and welcome tonight more
buildings to go down in Lagos Island
declares Governor Babu as he vowed to go
after those flouting safety regulations
and business district area says action
is
unacceptable it's yet another twist in
River's politics says former Governor PB
Governor fubara declares in political
leader of the state residents of the Moa
Council pitch tent with former Governor
n
Weeki and the minister ofar apologizes
to Nigerians over his comments accusing
them of wasting energy by keeping their
freezers and air conditioners running
when not at
[Music]
Hope
and on business news tonight opec's
latest report shows Nigeria's crude oil
production fell for the second straight
month to 1.23 million barrels per day in
March on sports news tonight the Premier
League will introduce semi-automated
offside technology next season in the
hope of producing the time it takes to
make V
decisions
from aband the nation's capital op rizes
for displaced persons in over 100
communities in Plateau State as the
government moves to resettle them in
their ancestral
homes and in international news from
London President Joe Biden has promised
Israel Ironclad support amid fears that
Teran could launch reprisals for an
attack that killed senior
[Music]
Iranians Governor Babu ofos state is
talking tough he says more buildings
will be brought down in Lagos Island
following what he describes as Spate of
infractions in the business district
area meanwhile the governor has ordered
the indefinite closure of the popular
dmu market after Tuesday's fire that got
to the area and mandated relevant
agencies in the state to go after those
flouting safety regulations in the
commercial hub he said this during his
visit to the site of The Inferno which
affected about 14 buildings our
correspondent Dar do brings us an
update over 48 hours after it is still a
live site here at Dum
Market the smoke although not as heavy
as that of the day one but still filters
in the
air with firemen continuing with the
damping
down Governor is making his first visit
to this site since this particular
incident well this is a familiar scene
especially at this
Market the governor announced that some
of the traders who lost valuables in the
INF
will be provided some
relief what I have seen here
is what could have been
prevented we don't have a full report
yet so I don't want to speculate but
initial
report that came to R was just gross
carelessness I would sit around and
speak to the other stakeholders and hear
how what amount
of supports what level of comfort what
level of
um um support will be rendering to some
of um um um the people that have been
affected and we will try and see how we
settle them very quickly and see how we
can get them back you know on their
feet but this
is an incident too
often very very condemnable and very
unacceptable the governor is worried
that residents and Traders here have
continually flouted safety regulations
mandating state agencies to attend to
these ises without
delay the market all around will be
closed today tomorrow until when we're
able to do a full assessment and to do a
proper cleanup of this entire area I
want to say without any how of doubt
that some other buildings are still
going to go down this is totally
unacceptable table we will not allow a
few people a few people who will not
comply with our rules with our
laws to put the lives of others in
danger fiscal
planning planning authorities lapka are
going to be having a difficult time with
me and when they have a difficult time
with me you will know they will come on
the
street at least 14 structures were
destroyed in this Inferno it is one with
the highest number of buildings affected
in one incident in Lagos Island the
closest was a similar fire outbreak at
the nearby balagu Market in 2020 where
more than eight buildings were affected
diary Channel's television
news over now to River weather seems to
be another Twist of events in the
state's politics with former Governor
Peter odili endorsing Governor s life
praising him for defending the interest
of the people Dr odil Who was the state
Governor between 1999 and 2007 said that
Governor fubara having secured his
election both through the ballot and the
court is now the political leader of
River State the former Governor was
speaking at the commissioning of a
primary healthc care center donated by
his Palo foundation in indoni his
hometown in aoni local government
area for standing up to your oath of
office
to defend the interest of all River's
people in accordance with the
constitution of the federal republic of
Nigeria you have done
that standing on firm
ground and with the strength and courage
of a
lion we are we are we are proud of you
politics is
over it is now time for governance and
you have hit the ground
running you have touched the critical
sectors in less than one year in
office our people say I should tell
you to stand firm with the
president align with his positive
policies and carry River's
people to the engine room of government
in the federal republic of
Nigeria for those who have not bothered
to pay
attention if you look at the map of
Nigeria the entire map of Nigeria is
sitting on River
State when River State cops Nigeria will
catch
cold
H so regard regard your office as key
and
vital don't look back it is not a matter
of age it is a matter of your people are
with
you and they asked me to tell
you
that you are the political leader of re
State local government area of River
State have declared the fct minister n
wi the leader of the PDP in River State
now the Sons and Daughters of the
Council made their position known during
a stakeholders meeting at the IM MOA
Council headquarters they also
reaffirmed their support for president
Bola tinu and thanked him for appointing
Mr R as fct
Minister this is a gathering of
politicians traditional rulers women
groups as well as other stakeholders of
equiry descent at the emoa local
government area Council of River
State they are here for a meeting and
their aim is to restate their support
for the minister of the federal capital
territory we are behind you leading the
group is a local government chairman CH
Lloyd who in his speech refers to Mr Wii
as the Undisputed leader of the PDP in
the states we are here to renew our
commitment to the renewed hope
agenda and to thank the president for
finding one of our own our
leader the leader of the people's
Democratic party in rer state chief
honorable
[Applause]
bar
for finding him worthy to be
appointed as the first
souer the first
sou to sit as Minister for the federal
capital territory interestingly the
former Chief of Staff who is also a
commissioner in the current
Administration as well as a member of
the State House of Assembly REO Mr
Lloyd's statement about the status of
the minister of the fct in River State
PDP it isic
and funny to see that instead of people
focusing on governance focusing on
delivering and discharging the
responsibility with which they s for
vote and they were voted for all hear
every day that wi did not do this and wi
did not do that is
wi I stand
with
with so my
I want to thank you for your
show of support at the end of the
exercise a communicate stating the
position of the assembly is read out
that we Ur Mr President to beware of
certain politicians who are currently
parading themselves in River State as
supporters of the U
Administration we are aware that these
politicians were are supporters of a
presidential candidate with whom they
malign
and discouraged the personality of Mr
President during the 2023 campaigns and
elections these
politicians
have
gathered under a fair political platform
to destabilize and make the system this
is yet another in a series of ongoing
political battles between supporters of
the former Governor and his successor
Sim alai fubara in their political face
off Charles oper room channels
television
news staying with political matters one
of the governorship aspirants on the
platform of the APC in noo state senator
jimo Ibrahim says he has a 10-point
development agenda if elected as
governor Mr Ibrahim said this in undo
City the headquarters of undo West local
government area where he visited to
Converse for vote ahead of the
forthcoming primary election of the
party
the leadership of the aiori movement is
meeting with the registered members of
the APC in all the 12 political Wards in
Ando West local government area of Ono
State the meeting is all about
convincing the eligible members of the
APC to cast their votes for Senator jimo
Ibrahim in the party's governorship
primary speaker with Channel's
television Senator Ibrahim expresses
Delight in the turnout of the members
for the meeting he also speaks on his
10o development agenda for Ono state if
elected as governor of the state I
talked about the
[Music]
in where we have 46 billion B deposited
in that place and we are not doing
anything with it and we don't have RADS
so if you look at the renew hope agenda
it's still about using this natural
resources you know to affect human
capacity to develop and that's what we
are trying to do to create weth you have
to open the top of Revenue if you want
to really develop the state without
taxing the people I one of my program is
that I will radicate personal income tax
during my time as a governor we call
that one tax integration there will be
no personal income tax some of the
members of the aori movement from the
local government reaffirmed their
support for Senator Ibrahim to clinch
the party's ticket Senator jimo I think
is actually very ready for this job I
think he's the most prepared is the most
experienced he has the capacity and he
well ready to take this opportunity to
be the next governor of state he has the
highest Network I've done my swart
analysis before I supported him so I
know he has the chance the big biggest
chance compared to the rest of the other
other competitors people believe Inori
people believe in Jim ibraim that is why
you see people in this Hall today as the
APC governorship primary Nate draws
closer the aspirants are put in final
touches for the dday members of their
Shori movement continue to seek the
support of other party members for
Senator jimo Ibrahim whom they are
convinced will come out victorious in
the
primary in part two after the break I'm
sorry for my comment the minister of par
apologizes tonight for accusing them of
wasting
energy please stay with
[Music]
us New Beginnings are always
colorful when we celebrate the start of
life's journey we marry in colors with
our proudly Nigerian duux pains now
available in any color express your
world however you want it visit a Dulux
color Center to get any color instantly
duux let's color are you ready to unlock
the future of healthcare join us at
medic West Africa the Premier Medical
exhibition happening at the Landmark
Center in losos from 17th to 19th
April 2024 with over 6,000 plus
attendees 180 plus exhibitors 32
countries represented eight product
categories three
conferences medic West is more than just
an exhibition it's a platform for
Innovation collaboration and learning
don't miss your chance to connect with
decision makers and professionals from
various regions all coming together over
3 Days To shape the future of
healthcare mark your calendars for April
17th to 19th
2024 The Duchess international hospital
caters to every aspect of the family's
health needs a One-Stop shop for
maternity and Child Health Services
emergency medicine and Critical Care
Medical and surgical subsp Specialties
DST and iare and a range of other subs
Specialties and services all available
at a single location right here in the
heart of ker and it really doesn't
matter if you're paying out of pocket
using your HMO or private insurance we
focus completely on providing that
worldclass affordable health care for
all the family at all
times
[Music]
do you know that you can now print all
your essential items for event without
even having to leave your home it's the
cast Prince combo deal for all events
yes weddings conferences birthdays
burials Etc starting from 495,000 naira
only you get 50 invites 50 A2 size
posters 506 page brochures one large
backdrop Banner one rollup Banner 50
jots with pens and 50 souer carrier bags
whatever event you're planning we can
adjust to your budget and quantities
just send your pictures and other
information through WhatsApp and we
shall send a design for your approval
approve your design and we will produce
with super high quality digital print
technology we can even arrange delivery
to your location call us now on
0913 56501 6 or 0812 794 9323 or visit
our social media Pages casrs digital
printing at Su
[Music]
speed welcome back if you just joined us
you're watching the news at 10 coming to
you live on channels television from the
lagos a reminder of our top
stories more buildings to go down in
Lagos Island declares Governor babaj
Desu as he vows to go after those
flouting safety regulations in the
business district
area it's yet another twist in River
State Politics as former Governor Pet o
backs Governor Fubar declares him
political leader of the state residents
of a MOA Council Peach tent with former
Governor n
we the minister of power apologizes to
Nigerians over his comment us using them
of wasting energy by keeping their
freezers and air conditioners running
when not at
[Music]
home and President Joe Biden promises
Israel Ironclad us supporter midf that
tran could launch reprisals for an
attack that killed senior
[Music]
Iranians
the nitan Navy ship lugard has arrested
an alleged drug Baron Alo laal with 620
pel of substance suspected to be
cannabis ativa or marijuana in kogi
state the commander nns lugard looja
commodor Moses aqu said this at the
Naval Base headquarters in Band of looja
local government area of Ki State while
handing over the suspects to ndlea
officials he urged those in the business
of illicit drugs to desist from such
facts warning that the long arm of the
law will surely catch up with
them away from crime matters the
minister of par Mr dibay DBU has tended
an unreserved apology to Nigerians for
criticizing their use of energy while
addressing a news conference in Abuja
last Thursday Mr Dau accused Nigerians
of wasting energy by keeping their
freezers and air conditioners running
even when not at home a practice he said
is due to cheap electricity his comment
however attracted criticism from
citizens for the minister during an
interview on our political program
politics today Mr DBU said he was sorry
for what he
said it was actually an innocent advice
with regards to energy consumption
management which we believe will go a
long way in reducing People's Energy
bills and that advice was actually
directed at those that we believe uh
because of the recent increase in tariff
you start enjoying 20 22 24 hours of uh
power supply what I said was that the
fact that the Tariff for band a which is
for 15% of the total uh electricity
consumers will increase by over 200%
does not necessarily Translate into 200%
increase in their electricity bills if
power is properly uh managed in terms of
consumption the example of the freezer
well he may might not have gone down
well with majority of Nigerians I would
say oh sorry about that it was never in
my intention to insult anybody uh it was
just out of my passion and my eagerness
to ensure that we make a change in this
sector which has suffered a lot of
setback for for some
years meanwhile for some residents and
business owners in Port harcour the
river state capital the hike in
electricity tariff is a cause for
concern and they are calling for a
reversal of the decision or equitable
distribution of power our correspondent
deah abalar visited some areas in Port
harcour and here is a her
report on April the 3D the minister of
power adayo adelabu announced a
substantial
240% increase in electricity tariffs
despite a position from organized labor
the federal government stands firm
defending the hike stating that only 1.5
million out of 12 million users fall
under the higher tar
category we went out of town to see
firsthand if it's true and only those
enjoying 20 hours of power supply are
feeling the pinch
this is a laaya housing estate a mixture
of residential and business premises
residents here say they get only 3 to 4
hours of power supply daily but have
noticed the height on their prepaid
meters I'm not find funny at all cuz the
light is not even being given like how
it's supposed to be like we're not even
satisfied with the lights like the power
supply is very very low this government
have failed Nigeria since the arrival of
the president tinti now nothing is going
on in this country everything is
increment increment increment
electricity is important even we are
paying we are paying certain things we
are not getting the value even now the
problem is would we pay 300% increment
and get the value of what we are paying
that is the point Mr s a business owner
around the vicinity explains to us how
electricity High bills compounding with
scany power supply eat deep into his
profit we we are spending more on for
again even with increment we don't even
see the light so it it Al it affect our
cost of operation the Nigeria labor
Congress NLC is making bold statements
with each head of information Benson OA
warning of a potential Showdown if T's
AR reverted to previous levels echoing
this sentiment Alex agore the NLC State
chairman stands firm in support of the
national stands considering the plight
of uh the Nigerians at this period where
people are already struggling in terms
of the price of goods and services and
uh the high rate of inflation and
government is coming with policy that
will inflict more poverty more hardship
on the people you know it's not
acceptable anywhere I think government
should be concerned about the wellbe of
the people that are living are not
bringing policy that will put them more
in has as residents and businesses in
Port haut continue to Grapple with the
effects of the electricity price hike
many are calling for a reversal to
subsidize rates or equitable
distribution of the promised 20 hours of
power supply deah Abal channels
television
news right let's get some more
perspective on this issue of increasing
electricity tariff which is indeed
coming amid complaints by Nigerian
about po power supply in the country
Channel's television analyst Mr La joins
us live from our budg Studios to examine
this great to have you on the news at 10
uh why has the problems in the past
sector remained intractable for
long thank you ha I I think uh just like
quite a number of our national
challenges we have not been able uh to
go to the root cause of uh the major
challenge in the power sector which in
my view and in the view of many of the
experts is the problematic privatization
sale of uh of of of the discos
especially and the genos because what
you have is a situation where those who
purchased the discos uh don't have the
uh the technical competence and they
also lack the financial muzzle to be
able to invest in the business and so
there is a liquidity crisis a clear
liquidity liquidity crisis in the sector
there is no cash flow that does not
encourage
investment and and the attempt to
increase the Tariff is is actually uh a
way that uh ner and and the the
companies are trying to solve the
liquidity crisis so in my view the main
problem is that we have not looked at
how can we fix the 40 privatization sale
that to that took place uh uh some time
ago in this country that is the
fundamental problem and it has to be
addressed all right so there are there
are indeed dient views you know
regarding the electricity tariff heke
but would you say it is Justified we
talk about the the band for consumers
ban a ban B and and all and all of that
what would you say concerning
this yeah so I I think it's important
for us Nigerians to understand that now
the power sector is a business and so uh
there has to be a cash flow for the
people in the business I think the
government has tried to explain that the
recent tariff I uh is only for about 15%
of the consumers at a particular
category the problem however is that the
Nigerian people do not see uh the
delivery of effect
service from the discour to Warrant any
kind of increase and like I have said
the problem that we have with the discos
is that they don't have the financial
modu they're not putting in the money
for instance to fix some of their old
equipments and and they are still doing
estimated billing for the for the better
part and so uh the people don't see the
services for which they pay but quite
frankly there will be a need for some
kind of resources money coming into that
sector and government is saying let us
see how we can increase tariff for those
who can pay and we can show some
Services all right I also say I would
suggest that it will be useful to also
find other means of bringing resources
and finances into the sector outside of
tariffs there ideas uh already about
that so what's the way forward very
quickly
so so so so I think first and foremost U
we should have a an all Society approach
to this problem namely that look this is
a failure of both the public and private
sector the public didn't sell to the
right people the people who bought it
couldn't run it as a as a matter of fact
there was a time there was insolvency so
we need to solve that problem we need to
come together and say what are we going
to do we need new investors okay to come
into into the business and also we need
new ideas some people have suggested an
energy fund uh which can be used to also
solve some of the liquidity crisis in
the sector and then we need the cement
deal the cement initiative to move
faster so that we can have repairs of
the transmission lines and the
distribution lines these
are that can take us forward we'll leave
that on Channel television analyst we
thank you for your thoughts on the news
thank you
a are the first civilian governor of old
ABIA State and former minister of
science technology and Innovation Draya
Anu has died Dr Anu who hiled from EO
State created partly from the old ABIA
state was an all progressives Congress
presidential aspirant in the 2023
election is reported to have died today
in a hospital in Abuja Dr honor was
appointed minister of Science and
Technology by former president Muhammad
bhari in November of 2015 a position he
held until he resigned in 2022 to
contest for the presidential ticket of
the APC at its primary but then lost to
president Bola nuu meanwhile Governor
Francis muu of a state has described Dr
anu's Death as sad saying he was a
thoroughbred politician and an advocate
of justice and fairness who stopped at
nothing at rendering best services to
his
people in the meantime the president has
been paying tribute to the former
Federal Minister and extending his
condolences to the hu family in
statement president bolu described him
as a luminous star in Nigeria's
political firmament and a principal
drawman in the founding of the APC and a
valiant partner in the victory of the
party in the 2015 elections the
president further celebrates him as an
accomplished scholar first class
engineer a man of proven integrity and
ever yielding to the highest standards
of rectitude President Tabu affirms that
Chief honor epitomizes Nigeria as he
believed in and defended Nigeria's Unity
advocated peace and promoted Fellowship
across the
niga still ahead on the news at 10
opec's latest report shows Na's crude
oil production fell for the second
straight month to 1.23 million barrels
per day in March that's on business news
please join us
[Music]
again investing in the Capital Market
can be tricky as it the numbers move in
different
directions sometimes the bull Bellows
other times it's the beer the
calls in all of these an investment
decision has to be
made on Capital Market we help you take
the right
decision join us at 700 p.m. every
Saturday only on channels television
Capital Market investment tips for
you
[Music]
welcome back the art and creative
Community is mourning the death of one
of its own a Hollywood actor pop abom
who drowned in River Anam in anambra
state on Wednesday after shooting a
movie at a location on nron movie actor
popularly known as Junior Pope
reportedly died on his way back from a
movie location alongside some persons
yet to be confirmed after their speed
capsized in the river reacting to the
incident the minister of art culture and
creative economy hanu musawa has
expressed deep shock over the tragic
occurrence which comes barely 48 hours
after the death of a countywood actress
saratu gadu minister maawa in the
statement described the Spate of debt in
the entertainment industry as horrific
and tragic saying it's a sad week for
the creatives and movie industry losing
great young talents and entertainment
providers
so let's head to the nation's capital
and Victoria long joh standing bar to
give us the very latest from our brid
Studios hello
Victoria hello AEL we continue here with
Plato State as displaced persons in over
100 communities and parts of the state
are to be resettled in their ancestral
homes before the fing season commences
the state task force settled with the
responsibility is a sharing the
internally displaced persons of Speedy
resettlement to their various
communities especially in areas of
security and reconstruction of destroyed
homes the task force on resettlement of
internally displaced persons setled by
the plateau state government has
commenced on the sport assessment and
interactive sessions with victims of
attacks affected across 121 communities
of mangu riam Bas and barin ly local
government areas of plateau State some
displaced persons have started returning
though with some anxiety and urge
governments to speedily commence the
resettlement agenda we are very
impressed and we we hope that the
government will hen up so that our
people will come back because this uh
farming season there are so many
challenges but we will plead if they
will make special Consignment as per
fertilizer for all the areas that have
been affected and particular are making
a case for my people the chairman of the
task force led the team to mangle for
the assessment and to review
preparations for the resettlement where
over 67 communities were affected it
will be done in
faces the immediate assignment now is to
those that we can provide security for
them to start working in their F another
team led by the Vice chairman visited
BOS where 53 communities were assessed
and part of the issues were also looking
out for also part of the amenities that
they also that would that they were
require to stay comfortably we're
looking at their worship centers we're
looking at the water points we're also
looking out for clinics and their
schools the transition committee
chairman of BOS local government area
expressed confidence that the displaced
persons will soon be resettled we are we
are we engaging the set government to
see that we uh P resources together so
that uh we will uh give this displaced
person sense of
belonging thank you very much sir as the
process for resettlement of internally
displaced persons across the affected
communities commences government is
expected to put in place necessary
measures that will facilitate the
resettlement of the affected
persons over to B State now where
Governor Bala Muhammad says he will put
aside political differences and
collaborate with the federal government
the despite being in opposition for the
sake of the state development the
governor said this during the annual
Derber event held at the government
house in belchi where he announced plans
to improve the State Health Facilities
with federal assistance our
correspondent hajar Ali
reports the Bui Emirates consisting of
King makers council members traditional
title holders and District heads are
paying traditional Salah homage to the
Govern
now this year marks the 110th darber
event since its Inception in 1914 during
the colonial Administration known as
haiki the festival takes place a day
after the eat celebration at the
government
house the Amir of Boi along with other
eminent personalities are here at the
new Grand Arena built by the governor to
watch the processions as the M of leads
the lineup of the
[Laughter]
procession
Hunters Warriors and horse riders
display their gallantry and
style the event showcases the
traditional regalia with beautifully
adorned horses as traditional music and
dance performances add to the Splendor
of the daa aimed at thrilling
[Music]
Spectators during the event the governor
receives greetings from each of the 50
the five processions various ethnic
groups residing in Boi also pay homage
demonstrating the festival's unifying
nature speaking in house the Emir of Boi
expresses deep appreciation to the
governor for his
leadership your Excellency
I wish to appeal to you to continue with
the developmental strides especially in
the areas of education and health care
and other things that make life better
for the
people Governor Muhammad in turn pledges
to continue partnering with the federal
government for the development of the
state as he announces new projects in
the offing our Hospital projects are
continuing and we are going to build
more more schools with we have declared
emergency on education we have accessed
a lot of funding from development
Partners we are very very the galadima
of poi's procession marks the end of the
processions and signals the peak of the
event the 's
[Music]
procession as the emia leaves the podium
and back to the ARA on Horseback
accompanied by Palace guards and
elements of royalty he greets the
governor to pay homage before departing
the government house for the palace
haera ALU channels television
news and the need to infuse right values
and reimagine in order to reposition
oneself has come to the fall at a
gathering of youths in Lagos for the
maiden addition of the Lagos conf
friend's courtesy of the young
professionals Club the event provided a
platform for notable personalities to
offer useful advice to the younger
generation on how to navigate life's
rough path without compromising
standards in the name of Jesus this is a
first edition of the Legos conference
put together by the young professionals
and is geared towards reemphasizing
value repositioning among the youths in
Nigeria these young professionals are
reminded that they can realize your
dreams if they are diligent despite the
high level of moral decadence especially
among young people as there's an urgent
need for value reorientation for us to
change the culture we have now we need
to do more than
prayer am I talking we need to do more
than what pray we have to insist on
doing what is
right whether in the way of God or in
the ways of life but that you will be an
influencer of valley that you will be an
impact enhancer that you will be a life
that creates value in other lives around
you values that lead people up and not
leave them down that you yourself will
be that vessel and you will invest in it
after the opening formalities the
conference then goes into another
session as panelists shed more light on
the thrust of the event
I want to tell the young
professional that the purpose and
objective of a m canot be overemphasized
in your journey of life he have forc you
to avoid the costly mistakes the Twist
and tongs that by sheer Grace and
tenacity these people have overcome one
of the things that define you are those
things you can say no to uh um the same
way one of the things that define you in
Life or part of the things that define
you in life are those things you don't
have and you aspire to it just tell us
what exactly your mindset is for these
young leaders one show way of making
Nigeria work is through the infusion of
the right values many people think about
what they want to get rather than what
they can give and that's why it's
important for us to bring together young
people into this place and have people
who have gone through that cycle of
value driven successes to speak to them
show them that you can succeed without
having to go through a crooked path if
you have the right persons with the
right values sitting in the right
offices the project Nigeria will be like
the success story of the corporate world
even in Nigeria submissions by different
speakers at the 2024 Lagos conference
organized by the young professionals is
an indication that Nigeria can attain
more enviable Heights if the right
values are inculcated by citizens
especially the
youth and that's it from Abuja is now
over to will ibong for business
news banking so easy so simple dstar 894
now to experience it you first First
[Music]
Bank
thank you Victoria and welcome to
business news Nigeria's crude oil
production has recorded its second
consecutive drop this year from 1.32
million barrels per day in February to
1.23 million Barrels in March and that's
according to opec's latest monthly oil
market report the 92,000 barrels per day
decline recorded in March brings the
total loss for the two months to about
196,000 barrels per day now looking at
the chart for Africa's Top O producers
within OPEC Libya narrowly overtakes
Nigeria with about 1.24 million barrels
per day produced in March meanwhile
Nigeria's oil recount Rose by three in
March climbing to 19 from February's
count of
16 now the chairman of bua group Samad
rabu has commended the steps being taken
by the federal government even as he
advised Nigerians to be patient as
reforms take time the businessman was
speaking after he paid a visit to
president B u in Lagos also speaking
after a separate meeting with the
president the group CEO of the Nigerian
National Petroleum Corporation limited
mikari said significant improvements
have occurred in the country's petroleum
Market we all need to come together and
uh support the government support their
policies you know the government means
well you know clearly and they are
trying to support Nigeria but we need to
be patient you know these reforms take
time without a doubt is not easy it's
not something that uh can be done within
in one day so we are working together
with the government especially now that
the president has you know established
you know this committee you know between
the government and the private sector so
we are working together we are
supporting each other we're advising the
government and the government is
listening that is very very important
the fact that the government is
listening you know means so much you
know to the private sector and I think
we'll get you know to the desired land
it's also a perfect opportunity to
reassure Mr President that his focus on
delivering gas into our markets both
domestic and international market
bringing back prosperity to our country
is right on cost and this is a tax that
will be delivered and very many obvious
things will will unfall in the coming
weeks it is very clear that uh uh
majority of our exports from this
country is petroleum as a to dat that
can earn uh foreign currency there
significant Improvement in the markets
in terms of pricing and also we're able
to establish some level of stability in
our project the combination of this is
bringing additional resources available
to our country and of course more than
anything there are clear monetary and
fiscal policies that the president and
this government has put in place that is
working and that is bringing about all
the changes that you are seeing in the
currency
market now staying with the economy the
debt management office zmo says it plans
to raise 450 billion Nara in its
upcoming Bond auction on April the 15th
this target is part of the DM's broad
strategy to generate up to 1.8 trillion
n through federal government bonds in
the second quarter of 2024 the auction
will offer 150 billiona for each of the
following bonds the newly issued fgn
April 2029 5year Bond the reopened 2031
7year Bond and the 2034 10year bond in
the first quarter of this year the DMO
raised about 2.39 trillion through fgn
bonds with the largest issuance recorded
in
February still speaking of raising funds
fbn Holdings PLC has announced his plans
to raise up to 300 billion n through
public offerings private placement and
rights issued this year in a statement
sent to the Nigerian exchange limited
ngx the listed Financial Services Group
says the capital raise would be from
either the domestic or International
Capital Market it added that the planned
raise is subject to approval by the
regulatory authorities and its
shareholders at an extraordinary general
meeting to be held later in the
month now outside our Shores the
European Central Bank ECB has kept
interest rates steady at 4% for the
fifth consecutive meeting but strongly
hints at an imminent rate Court amid
uncertainties about the US Federal
Reserve actions in his statement the ECB
stressed the importance of factors like
inflation Outlook underlying Dynamics
and monetary policy transmission June is
now seen as a critical month with
expectations mounting for potential rate
reductions meanwhile the European
markets Clos was lower on Thursday after
the ECB held rate steady at a record
high of 4% on the flip side we saw a
rebound in the US markets let's check
out the numbers and the performance of
other major stocks markets around the
[Music]
world
and that's business news is back to a
for the rest of the news at
10 banking so easy so simple dial 894
now to experience it you first first
B thank you will former American
football star turned actor OJ Simpson
has died after a battle with cancer the
7 the six-year-old became popular in the
1990s for his controversial trial and
acquit over the double murder of his
ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson and her
friend Ron Goldman here's Simon KY with
other international news in around the
world in
five good evening and welcome to the
channels studios here in London with
your international news around the world
in
five President Joe Biden has promised
Israel Ironclad us support amid fears
that Teran could launch reprisal
for an attack that killed senior
Iranians we also want to address the
Iranian threat Mr Biden warned that Iran
is threatening to launch a significant
attack after Israel struck the Iranian
Consulate in Syria 10 days ago earlier
Iran's leader said the Israeli attack in
Damascus was equivalent to an attack on
Iran itself it is unclear what form any
reprisal attack would take to launch a
signif they're threatening to launch a
significant attack on Israel as I told
prime minister Netanyahu our commitment
to Israel's security against these
threats from Iran and its proxies is
Ironclad let me say it again Ironclad
we're going to do all we can to protect
Israel's security a major power plant
near keev has been completely destroyed
by Russian strikes early on Thursday
that's according to the Energy company
Center
nuro tripa power plant was the largest
provider of electricity for three
regions including ke Russia has long
been deliberately and systematically
targeting Ukraine's Energy System the
strikes are thought to have destroyed
the Transformer the turbines and the
generators the center nuro boss said the
plant was targeted by multiple missiles
staff on shift were able to escape he
said because they ran for cover as soon
as the first drone
hit it was the most spectacular trial
ever held in Vietnam benefiting one of
the greatest Bank frauds the world has
ever seen 67y old old trong Milan was
convicted of taking out $44 billion in
loans from The Saigon Commercial Bank
the verdict requires her to return $27
billion as some prosecutors said may
never be recovered some believe the
death penalty is the Court's way of
trying to encourage her to return some
of the missing
billions at least 17 Pakistani pilgrims
have died in a bus crash while traveling
to a shrine in Balochistan for Eid the
accident occurred when the V lost
control before falling into a ravine
more than 40 are also being treated for
injuries in Karachi and police have
warned casualties could rise High
fatality crashes are common in Pakistan
often caused by driver error or poorly
maintained
roads at least 100 Russians have asked
Vladimir Putin for help in a city struck
by the worst flooding ever recorded
chanting shame on you at local officials
who they said had done too little to
help their plight Russia declared an
emergency in the orur region near
Kazakhstan after the Ural River Europe's
third longest river swelled several
meters in hours and burst through a dam
embankment in the city of Ork with their
properties either destroyed or severely
damaged many people are unhappy with the
compensation offered by authorities some
are also unhappy that the dam embankment
built in 2010 was unable to defend their
City stunning artworks have been
uncovered in a new excavation at Pompei
the ancient ancient Roman city buried in
an eruption from Mount vvus in
ad79 archaeologists say the Fresco are
among the finest to be found in the
ruins of the ancient site mythical Greek
figures such as Helen of Troy are
depicted on the high Black Walls of a
large banqueting Hall the rooms near
complete Mosaic floor incorporates more
than a million individual white
tiles pompe is a a a city of horrible
stories for the people not for the
houses for the frescos for for the
object but for the people yeah we start
to study the Reconstruction of the story
of these people to give them a new
memory only in Pompei you can see the
life of the people of the Roman people
and French athlete ANUK garer has
attempted to break the Rope climbing
record by climbing a 110 M rope to the
second floor of the Eiffel
Tower she reached her goal in just 18
minutes the two-time world Obstacle
Course Champion trained for a year
before attempting The Climb her record
has not yet been validated by the
Guinness Book of World Records but she
said this did not take away from her
accomplishment and that's your
international news around the world in
five now back to the channels studios in
Lagos
[Music]
thank you Simon welcome to sports news
the confederation of African football
cup is expected to make a statement on
the kickoff date for this year's Africa
women's cup of nation that will be
hosted by Morocco speaking to China's
television in London C executive
committee member amaju pinnick confirmed
it is on the top agenda for discussion
at next week's meeting in
Morocco after that I can be
authoritative but for now I don't think
I have the locus to speak on that okay
give me a background why did we get into
this situation because we never have
this sort of problem with the men I
cannot give you a background because of
issues in C there's a modicom of
philosophy that has to do with privacy
in terms of issues like this it's quite
sensitive until we discuss it and the
appropriate Authority in C should come
out to speak on it unless they say pic
you can go and speak on it I cannot with
all your respect the women's football is
a major priority for
C we introduced the champions for women
and we have started it and we're not
sling
down the English Premier League will use
semi auto automated offside technology
before the end of the year clubs
unanimously agree to introduce the
technology next season after meeting of
Top Flight teams earlier today and its
implementation is expected to cut the
average length of a VR check for offside
by 30 seconds semi-automated offside is
already used in the Champions League and
Syria R while not exactly the same
system it was also used at the World Cup
in Qatar in
Jan Luca machini gave Roma a slender
advantage in tonight's Europa League
quarterfinal with AC Milan after netting
the only goal in a one- nil win at the
sanero Jonas Hoffman and Victor bonface
scored after coming off the bench as bam
Leverkusen beat West Ham 2neil At Home
Atlanta stunned and fielded as Jan
luucas kamaka are scored twice in a 3-
new win to leave Liverpool with a
mountain to climb to reach the Europa
League s
finals that's it on Sports it's back to
you a
[Music]
yourday many thanks Chris the chairman
of dangote group Mr aliku dangote says
the significant reduction in the diesel
prize by his Refinery will have a
positive effect on Nigeria's inflation
rate he made this known on Wednesday
during the briefing with journalists
following his homage visit to president
Bola tinu for the edil F in
Lagos one of the major issue that we've
had was the uh you know the Nara
devaluation that was actually that has
gone very aggressive up to about
1,900 but right now we are back to
almost 1,25 1,300 which is a good uh you
know reprieve and uh you can see quite a
lot of uh things have actually G even
people now when you go to the market for
example uh something that will produce
locally like A4 or whatever people will
charge you more why because they paying
very high prices on diesel and what we
did for example in our Refinery we
started selling even diesel at about
1,200 for
1,650 but that can help quite a lot
because if you are transporting locally
produced goods Rice and other stuff you
are paying 1,650 now you are paying 2/3
of that amount to 1,200 it's a lot of uh
difference you know people don't know
that can actually help to bring
inflation down immediately and I'm sure
when the inflation figures are out for
the next month you see that there's
quite a lot of improvement in the uh uh
inflation uh you know rate so step at a
time and I'm sure you know the bank I
mean the government is working around
the the clock to make sure that things
get much better because it is in their
it is in their own interest it's in
interest of everybody for Nigerians to
get things
better and the main news again Governor
Babu today said more buildings will have
to go down in Lagos Island as they vow
to go after those flouting safety
regulations in the business district
area that's the news attent tonight
thank you for watching I'm I to have a
good night
[Music]
for
hello and welcome to another fantastic
episode of entertainment news on
channels television